ABDULLAH HASHIM

+966-595585131 | Abdullah97Hashim@gmail.com | Saudi Arabia, Riyadh

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdullah-hashim/

SUMMARY

A Self-starting, intellectually curious and creative Computer Science fresh graduate with proven experience in frontend Development. Able to apply UI/UX concepts to improve the usability for the users, and delivering full projects within the provided time frame.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ministry Of Justice | Software Engineer | JUL 2019 - Now | Saudi Arabia, Riyadh

Real Estate Digitization Project - Vision Realization Office

• Working as frontend developer using Angular framework

THE SEARCH BASE | Co-Founder & Software Developer | DEC 2018 - Now | UK, London

TheSearchBase is startup where it provides a software as service (SaaS) that helps companies to market their recruitment services using our smart chat-bot application

- Architected the system from operation requirements to development requirements
- Developed the major UI components using React.js framework

SAUDI ARAMCO | COOP INTERN | JUL 2018 - JAN 2019 | Saudi Arabia, Dhahran

EXPEC Computer Center - Petroleum Engineering Application Services Department Reservoir Engineering Systems Division

- Designed and developed a new web application, using Angular framework
- Analyzed users' engagement with the applications and developed user experience

AWARDS & ACTIVITIES

WA'ED HACKATHON | SECOND PLACE | DEC 2018

Won the 2nd place among 150 participants over the kingdom in the parking solutions challenge

- Led the team during the hackathon
- Collaborated in designing the business model and analyzing the market size
- Prototyped and presented the idea

SAUDI ARAMCO UPSTREAM HACKATHON | FIRST PLACE | DEC 2018

Won the first place among 107 participants in the Automated Seismic Data Interpretation

- Designed an algorithm to automate seismic interpretations
- Utilized seismic attributes in the automation

EDUCATION

YANBU UNIVERSITY COLLEGE | SEP 2014 - MAY 2019

Bachelor of Computer Science with a GPA (3.5/4) - Web Application Development Track

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML CSS Javascript
- Angular Framework
- React Framework
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- Wire-framing
 Flowcharts
- Data Analysis
- Image Processing
 - Nodejs
 - MySQL

Python Flask

COURSES

FULLBRIDGE U ONLINE AT MISK | DEC 2017

Fullbridge intensive course which mainly included:

Creative problem solving skills, Data analysis technologies, and Project planning